Guide to the James Murray Luck Papers SC0181
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
James Murray Luck papers
1930-1979
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Luck, James Murray
SC0181
5.5 Linear Feet
Primarily correspondence and subject files relating to Professor Luck's professional activities, the Stanford Chemistry Department and his position as acting Science Attaché at the United States embassies in London, Stockholm and Bern.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of J. Murray Luck, 1977-1980.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Professor of biochemistry at Stanford (1926-1965; emeritus, 1965- ).
Description of the Collection
Primarily correspondence and subject files relating to Professor Luck's professional activities, the Stanford Chemistry Department and his position as acting Science Attaché at the United States embassies in London, Stockholm and Bern.
Luck, James Murray; Luck, James Murray; United States. Embassy. Sweden.; United States. Embassy. Switzerland.; Stanford University. Department of Chemistry; Palo Alto Coop.; Palo Alto Coop.; Taylor, C. U.; United States. Embassy. Gt. Brit.; United States.. Embassy (Sweden); Taylor, C. U.; United States.. Embassy (Switzerland); Clark, Griffin.; Clark, Griffin.; United States.. Embassy (Great Britain)
- Papers, 1933-1979
  - Stanford Student Housing Association, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - AAAS Publication Symposium, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - AAAS Parliament of Science, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - International Conference on Scientific Information, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Palo Alto Credit Union - Its history, circa 1937 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Various trips, 1949-1951 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - AAAS Pacific Division - Executive Committee, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - US Exchange Mission to USSR, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Scientific Information Conference, 1961 November (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, while Science Attache, Bern, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, while Science Attache, Bern, circa 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Crackpot suggestions received, 1962-1964 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Science seminar, Foreign Service Institute, 1968 May (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with Dr Henry Baden, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Acting Science Attache, US Embassy, London, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Science seminar, Foreign Service Institute, 1967 October (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Acting Science Attache, US Embassy, London, Correspondence with Arthur Pardee, Jr. (State Dept.), Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Acting Science Attache, US Embassy, Stockholm, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Sir Hugh Ennor, correspondence, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Alex Von Muralt, 1964-1976 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1967-1977 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1971-1976 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1964-1970 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1961-1967 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Columbia University Press, "Science in Switzerland", Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - State Department and NSF, re: "Science in Switzerland", etc., 1964-1972 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - "Science in Switzerland" author correspondence, Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence from people receiving complimentary copies of "Science in Switzerland", Undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - "Science in Switzerland" miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - First Teaching Institute, American Medical College, Undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - American Society of Biological Chemists, Undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Wartime work on blood plasma and serum albumen, Undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Wartime work monthly requests for proteins, Undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Wartime work on plasma etc, Undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Wartime work on plasma etc, Undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Wartime work, correspondence re: serum albumen processing and sterilization, Undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Wartime work miscellaneous, Undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Stanford Chemistry Department, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - American Cancer Society Committee on Personnel for Research, Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with Paul Boyer, Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence with Clark Griffin, Undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Beginnings of NSF, Undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - IUPAC, Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence with Commission on proteins of IUPAC, Undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Commission on Biological Nomenclature, Undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - IUPAC, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Coordinating committee, 1957-1958 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - IUPAC, Undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - IUPAC, Undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - IUPAC Conference, Undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - IUPAC Section on Biochemistry General, 1954-1955 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Section on Biochemistry, 1949-1950 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Section on Biochemistry, 1950-1953 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence with Donald W. Krupke, Undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with Kennethy Murray, Undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - UNESCO Report, Paris, 1949 June 20-25 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Committee on Biochemistry NRC, and National Committee IUPAC, 1951-1953 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - NRC, IUPAC, and W.A. Noyes, Undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Royal Society Conference on Scientific Information London, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Chemistry Affiliates, 1972-1976 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Luck, Switzerland; Correspondence with President of Stanford, J.E.W. Sterling, 1958-1964 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence with Detleve Bronk, Undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Melanoma, Undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Population, Undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence with Carl F. Cori, Undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Unsorted material, 1952-1958 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Unsorted material, 1941-1945 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Unsorted material, 1946-1949 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Unsorted material, 1950-1955 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Unsorted material, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Unsorted material, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Unsorted material, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Unsorted material, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Unsorted material, 1960-1961 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Unsorted material, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Unsorted material, 1963-1965 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Unsorted material, 1966-1970 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Unsorted material, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Unsorted material, 1974-1975 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Unsorted material, 1976-1979 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Aebi, Hugo, Undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Alhouse Realty Inc., 1962-1964 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - American Board of Clinical Chemistry, 1947-1955 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Ennor, Hugh, Undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - "Experiences with Swiss Schools", 1963 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Genealogical charts, Undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Griffin, Clark, Undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Luck, Norville Edward, Undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Palo Alto Coop, Its Beginnings, 1933-1934 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Palo Alto Coop, Its Beginnings, 1935-1936 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Palo Alto Coop, Its Beginnings, 1941-1949 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Palo Alto Coop, Its Beginnings, 1950-1972 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Palo Alto Coop Organization, Undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Teachers Insurance and Annuity Association of America, Undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Travel to London, etc, 1955 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - University of California, at Berkeley, Inauguration of President Clark Kerr, Undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - US Embassy, Bern, Switzerland, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - US Embassy, Bern, Switzerland, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - US Embassy, Bern, Switzerland, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - US Embassy, Bern, Switzerland, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - US Embassy, Bern, Switzerland: Science Attache, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - US Embassy, Bern, Switzerland, miscellaneous, Undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - US Embassy, London, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - US Embassy, Stockholm, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Von Muralt, Alex, 1964-1976 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Speech for Ambassador Robert M. McKinney, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Speech, Senator Stanford's views on Activities Concerning Cooperation, Undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Article, Malnutrion and poverty, Undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Article, Metabolism of nutrition study, Undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Palo Alto Housing Authority Notebook, Undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence and information, Undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Architect, Undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Reading material, 1946-1948 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Finance, Undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Bulletins, Undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Serum Albumin Conference Minutes, 1942-1944 (Box 13)
  - Scientific Mission to the USSSR, by J. Murray Luck, 1960 (Box 13)
  - Clark, Luck, Taylor, 1929-1931 (Box 13)
  - Letters, typescripts, reprints (Box 14, Box 15)